Guide to the St. Peter's Episcopal Church, Pittsburgh, Pa. Records, 1852-1958 AIS.1982.15
ULS Archives & Special Collections
St. Peter's Episcopal Church, Pittsburgh, Pa. Records
1852-1958
ULS Archives & Special Collections
St. Peter's Episcopal Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
AIS.1982.15
1 microfilm_reel (873 frames)
This collection contains the records of St. Peter's Episcopal Church, Pittsburgh (Oakland), Pa. It includes a historical sketch, parish registers, minutes of the Women's Guild, register of church services, deed to Burgwin pew, correspondence, newsclippings, and photographs.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection contains the records of St. Peter's Episcopal Church, Oakland, Pittsburgh, Pa. It includes a historical sketch, parish registers, minutes of the Women's Guild, register of church services, deed to Burgwin pew, correspondence, newsclippings, and photographs. Series I includes a historical sketch of the church, 1850-1918. Sereis II includes Parish registers, 1852-1958. These registers contain baptisms, communicants, confirmations, marriages, burials, parishoners, families, church offerings, and rectors. Series III contains the minutes of the Women's Guild of St. Peter's, November, 1916 - October, 1928. Series IV contains a register of church services and the deed to pew number 50.
Series V includes miscellaneous correspondence concerning the relocation of the church and the designation of the church as a national historic landmark. Series VI includes newsclippings about the relocation of the church building, change of rectors, church social and educational activities, 85th anniversary, national landmark status, and architectural style. Series VII includes photographs of the church facade, Grant and Diamond streets before relocation; the church as it stands on Fifth and Craft Avenues; and photos of church groups and the church basketball team.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These records were microfilmed, with permission, by the Archives of Industrial Society, September 1982.
Existence and Location of Originals
Original records in the possession of St. Peter's Episcopal Church.
Previous Citation
St. Peter's Episcopal Church, Pittsburgh, Pa. Records, 1852-1958, AIS.1982.15, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
St. Peter's Episcopal Church, Pittsburgh (Oakland) Pa. Records, 1852-1958, AIS Micro 82:15
Pittsburgh (Pa.) -- Church history; Church records and registers -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Church records; Church buildings -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Churches and Synagogues; Episcopal Church -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; St. Peter's Episcopal Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
- History, I.
  - Historical Sketch of St. Peter's Church, 1850-1918 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 1, Reel 1)
- Parish Registers, II.
  - Volume 1, December, 1852 - September, 1874 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 1, Reel 1)
  - Volume 2, 1852 - September, 1901 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 1, Reel 1)
  - Volume 3, June, 1902 - March, 1921 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 1, Reel 1)
  - Volume 4, October, 1918 - December, 1929 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 1, Reel 1)
  - Volume 5, September, 1927 - December, 1958, July, 1966 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 1, Reel 1)
- Minutes of the Women's Guild, III.
  - Volume 1, November, 1916 - October, 1928 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 1, Reel 1)
  - Volume 2, 1929 - January, 1939 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 1, Reel 1)
- Register of Church Services, IV.
  - Volume 1, October, 1928 - January, 1951 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 1, Reel 1)
  - Deed to Pew Number 50 (held by Hill Burgwin), April 23, 1867 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 1, Reel 1)
- Correspondence, V.
  - Miscellaneous, April - December, 1972 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 1, Reel 1)
- Newspaper Clippings, VI.
  - Volume 1, January, 1901 - October, 1972 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 1, Reel 1)
- Photographs, VII.
  - Volume 1, 1909-1915 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 1, Reel 1)